# Isidor Kaplan

isidorjkaplan@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/isidorjkaplan | transcript.pdf

## ABOUT ME

Computer engineer specializing in FPGA design, low-latency trading systems, and high-performance C++ software. Currently an FPGA Engineer at Headlands Technologies, with prior experience at Hudson River Trading and Intel developing production-grade hardware and software. Experienced in full-lifecycle FPGA and embedded systems design, with award-winning academic performance and top recognition in Computer Engineering at the University of Toronto.

#### EXPERIENCE

## **Headlands Technologies**

 $June\ 2024-Present$ 

 $FPGA\ Engineer$ 

Chicago, IL

- Engineered low-latency trading infrastructure, improving stability, scalability, and system performance
- Full-lifecycle FPGA design: specification, implementation, testing, verification, and deployment
- Developed high-performance software drivers and testing/verification frameworks for trading applications

#### **Hudson River Trading**

June 2023 – August 2023

Software Engineer (Intern)

New York, NY

Toronto, ON

- Design modern C++ multi-threaded, high-performance, networked, timing-accurate market-simulation tools
- Extend proprietary C++ exception-handling framework with improved stack-tracing capabilities %

Intel FPGA Engineer (Intern) May 2022 – May 2023

• Optimized next-generation FPGA routing architecture improving simulations results in VPR and Quartus

- Developed high-performance C++ graph tools to operate on FPGA routing architecture representations
- Developed Python tool for automated complex data visualization, reducing analysis time for experiments

## University Of Toronto

Sept 2021 - April 2024

Teaching Assistant

Toronto, ON

• TA for Operating Systems, Computer Organization, Programming Fundamentals, and Software Comm & Design, covering concurrency, memory, CPU design, Verilog, embedded programming, C++, and data structures.

Rocscience

May 2021 – August 2021

Software Engineer (Intern)

Toronto, ON

• Redesigned CPillar, a \$995/license C++ geological analysis software, enabling the first major update in years

#### University Of Toronto – iQua Research Group

May 2020 – August 2020

ML/AI Researcher (Intern)

Toronto, ON

• Developed advanced reinforcement learning models using PyTorch, applied to congestion control, edge computing, and network-adaptive coding, resulting in the publication of two conference research papers

#### EDUCATION

# University Of Toronto

Sept 2019 - June 2024

Toronto. ON

B.A.Sc in Computer Engineering

- Obtained 4.0/4.0 Cumulative GPA and 95.3% Cumulative Average
- Awarded Adel S. Sedra Gold Medal for highest grades in Computer Engineering, Class of 2024
- Awarded Annual Top Student Award from Dept of Electrical and Computer Engineering (2020-21 and 2021-22)
- Awarded Charles Edwin Trim (2022), BFMI Sesquicentennial Trust (2021), and In-Course (2020) Scholarships

#### **Academic Publications:**

IEEE ICC-SAC 2023

% Ivory: Learning Network Adaptive Streaming Codes

IEEE IWQoS 2022

**%** Deep Learning to Identify Ceramic Insulators and Detect Physical Damages

IEEE CEIDP 2021

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages & Tools: System Verilog, Modern C++, C, Python, Vivado, Quartus, Java, Assembly

Systems & Concepts: Low-latency, concurrency, FPGA design, CPU design, embedded programming

Algorithms & Math: Data structures, linear algebra, probability, control theory, multivariate calculus, ML/AI